[{"question": "What is a String in C Language.?", "option1": "A) String is a new Data Type in C", "option2": "B) String is an array of Characters with null character as the last element of array.", "option3": "C) String is an array of Characters with null character as the first element of array", "option4": "D) String is an array of Integers with 0 as the last element of array.", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "Choose a correct statement about C String.\nchar ary[]=\"Hello..!\";", "option1": "A) Character array, ary is a string.", "option2": "B) ary has no Null character at the end", "option3": "C) String size is not mentioned", "option4": "D) String can not contain special characters.", "ans": "A"}, {"question": "What is the Format specifier used to print a String or Character array in C Printf or Scanf function.?", "option1": "A) %c", "option2": "B) %C", "option3": "C) %s", "option4": "D) %w", "ans": "C"}, {"question": "What is the output of C Program with Strings.?\nint main()\n{\n    char ary[]=\"Discovery Channel\";\n    printf(\"%s\",ary);\n    return 0;\n}\n", "option1": "A) D", "option2": "B) Discovery Channel", "option3": "C) Discovery", "option4": "D) Compiler error", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "What is the output of C Program with Strings.?\nint main()\n{\n    char str[]={'g','l','o','b','e'};\n    printf(\"%s\",str);\n    return 0;\n}\n", "option1": "A) g", "option2": "B) globe", "option3": "C) globe\\0", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "What is the output of C Program with Strings.?\nint main()\n{\n    char str[]={'g','l','o','b','y','\\0'};\n    printf(\"%s\",str);\n    return 0;\n}\n", "option1": "A) g", "option2": "B) globe", "option3": "C) globe\\0", "option4": "D) Compiler error", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "How do you convert this char array to string.?\nchar str[]={'g','l','o','b','y'};", "option1": "A) str[5] = 0;", "option2": "B) str[5] = '\\0'", "option3": "C) str[]={'g','l','o','b','y','\\0'};", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "What is the output of C Program.?\nint main()\n{\n    int str[]={'g','l','o','b','y'};\n    printf(\"A%c \",str);\n    printf(\"A%s \",str);\n    printf(\"A%c \",str[0]);\n    return 0;\n}\n", "option1": "A) A A A", "option2": "B) A Ag Ag", "option3": "C) A*randomchar* Ag Ag", "option4": "D) Compiler error", "ans": "C"}, {"question": "What is the output of C Program with arrays.?\nint main()\n{\n    char str[]={\"C\",\"A\",\"T\",\"\\0\"};\n    printf(\"%s\",str);\n    return 0;\n}\n", "option1": "A) C", "option2": "B) CAT", "option3": "C) CAT\\0", "option4": "D) Compiler error", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " What is the maximum length of a C String.?", "option1": "A) 32 characters", "option2": "B) 64 characters", "option3": "C) 256 characters", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program with strings.?\nint main()\n{\n    char str1[]=\"JOHN\";\n    char str2[20];\n    str2= str1;\n    printf(\"%s\",str2);\n    return 0;\n}\n", "option1": "A) JOHN", "option2": "B) J", "option3": "C) JOHN\\0", "option4": "D) Compiler error", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " What is the output of C Program with arrays.?\nint main()\n{\n    char str[25];\n    scanf(\"%s\", str);\n    printf(\"%s\",str);\n    return 0;\n}\n//input: South Africa\n", "option1": "A) South", "option2": "B) South Africa", "option3": "C) S", "option4": "D) Compiler error", "ans": "A"}, {"question": " What is the output of C program with strings.?\nint main()\n{\n    char str[2];\n    scanf(\"%s\", str);\n    printf(\"%s\",str);\n    return 0;\n}\n//Input: South\n", "option1": "A) So", "option2": "B) South", "option3": "C) Compiler error", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " What is the output of C Program with strings.?\nint main()\n{\n    char str[2];\n    int i=0;\n    scanf(\"%s\", str);\n    while(str[i] != '\\0')\n    {\n        printf(\"%c\", str[i]);\n        i++;\n    }\n    return 0;\n}\n//Input: KLMN\n", "option1": "A) KL", "option2": "B) KLMN", "option3": "C) Compiler error", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " What is the output of C Program with String Pointer.?\nint main()\n{\n    char country[]=\"BRAZIL\";\n    char *ptr;\n    ptr=country;\n    while(*ptr != '\\0')\n    {\n        printf(\"%c\", *ptr);\n        ptr++;\n    }\n    return 0;\n}\n", "option1": "A) B", "option2": "B) BRAZIL", "option3": "C) Compiler error", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " How do you accept a Multi Word Input in C Language.?", "option1": "A) SCANF", "option2": "B) GETS", "option3": "C) GETC", "option4": "D) FINDS", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " Choose a correct C Statement about Strings.", "option1": "A) PRINTF is capable of printing a multi word string.", "option2": "B) PUTS is capable of printing a multi word string.", "option3": "C) GETS is capable of accepting a multi word string from console or command prompt", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " What is the output of C Program with String Pointers.?\nint main()\n{\n    char *p1 = \"GOAT\";\n    char *p2;\n    p2 = p1;\n    printf(\"%s\", p2);\n}\n", "option1": "A) G", "option2": "B) GOAT", "option3": "C) Compiler error", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " What is the output of C Program with String arrays.?\nint main()\n{\n    char *p1 = \"GOAT\";\n    char *p2;\n    p2 = p1;\n    p2=\"ANT\";\n    printf(\"%s\", p1);\n}\n", "option1": "A) ANT", "option2": "B) GOAT", "option3": "C) G", "option4": "D) A", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " What is the output of C Program with String Arrays.?\nint main()\n{\n    char p[] = \"GODZILLA\";\n    int i=0;\n    while(p[i] != '\\0')\n    {\n        printf(\"%c\",*(p+i));\n        i++;\n    }\n}\n", "option1": "A) G", "option2": "B) GODZILLA", "option3": "C) Compiler error", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "B"}]
